Umesh Chaudhary

Python/Django Developer

Self-motivated Python Developer with a high level of experience working on multiple Django based projects. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Always ready and excited to learn new technologies .

umesschaudhary@gmail.com +9779867989536 linkedin.com/in/umschaudhary

EXPERIENCE

Upwork, Remote— Python/Django Freelance Developer

July 2020 - Present

• Worked with various clients and various Django based projects.

Aayulogic, Kathmandu, Nepal — Python/Django Developer

Feb 2020 - July 2020

- Maintained existing web apps (DJango Rest Framework, PostgreSQL, Django ORM,OOP)
- Followed TDD approaches of the software development paradigm to ensure that software requirements were met
- Integrated various third party libraries like Python Social Auth

Purwanchal Digital Media Technologies, Biratnagar, Nepal — Django Developer

Sep 2018 - March 2019

- Worked on Pure Django Based Projects.
- Continuous maintenance and troubleshooting of Django projects (Django, PostgreSQL, Gitlab)

Zeftware Solutions, Biratnagar, Nepal — *Django Developer*

Sep 2018 - March 2019

- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- Developed UI with front-end technologies like HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Ajax
- Deployed project on Heroku and Digital Ocean

EDUCATION

Tribhuvan University,
Biratnagar, Nepal — B.SC. in Computer Science and Information Technology

SKILLS

- Django
- Python3
- Javascript
- HTML5
- Css/Bootstrap
- Sql/Postgresql
- Docker
- Git
- Linux
- Ngnix

LANGUAGES

- English
- Nepali